Guide to the Ruth Steinkraus-Cohen Collection MS 056
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Ruth Steinkraus-Cohen Collection
1800s-1940s
MS 056
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
5.0 Linear feet
The collection is comprised of mostly of sheet music which span the years 1800 to the 1960s. Also included are publicity photographs and other images of Steinkraus in her career as a pianist, radio host and activist for world peace.
Steinkraus-Cohen, Ruth, 1920-2002
Biographical/Historical note
Ruth Steinkraus-Cohen was born and raised in Cleveland, Ohio, and lived most of her life in Westport, Connecticut, and London. She attended The Thomas School, Vassar College, and became a trained pianist at the Julliard School of Music. During her career she was also a singer, editor, radio host, bibliophile, journalist, and activist for world peace.
In 1956, while serving as Eleanor Roosevelt’s secretary to the World Federation of the United Nations Association, she became a life-long committed supporter of the United Nations. She received national and international praise for her work on behalf of the UNA, the private, non-profit group that supports the U.N.’s work.
Ruth also organized the UNA-CT and UNA of Southwestern CT and eventually became a national board member of UNA-USA and vice president of UNA-UK, Westminster. During her life, Ruth won numerous awards for her service to music and the United Nations. Ruth Steinkraus-Cohen died on May 26, 2002.
Scope and Contents note
The collection is comprised of sheet music and photographs which span the years 1800 to the 1960s. The music scores are divided into seven series based on type of music. 1.Unbound Sheet Music, 2. Autographed Sheet Music, 3. Bound Scores, 4. Miscellaneous Music Scores, 5.Operas/Oratories/Vocal Music, 6. School Songs/Training Schools, and 7. Photographs.
Also included are publicity photographs and other images of Steinkraus in her career as a pianist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The collection was a bequest from the estate of the late Ruth Steinkraus-Cohen. In 2002, her brother, Bill Steinkraus, arranged for the transfer of about 2,000 books, 2,500 performing editions and scores, and long runs of 18 international musical journals to the Haas Library.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement note
The collection is grouped into seven series:
1. Unbound sheet music 2. Autographed sheet music 3. Bound scores 4. Miscellaneous music scores 5. Operas/oratories/vocal music 6. School songs and training schools 7. Photographs
Steinkraus-Cohen, Ruth, 1920-2002; Music--18th century.; Music--19th century.; Opera.; Photographs.; Piano music.; School songbooks.; Sheet music.
- 17th-18th Unbound Sheet Music
  - Lecarpentier, Adolphe Clair, 1809-1869. title: l'elisre d'amore Publisher: Chabal, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    forehanded piano
  - Unknown title: The Marrigige Pretty Between John and Betty Publisher: N.P., undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    n/a
  - Zanolini, Antonio, 1791-1877. title: La Vi a deux Publisher: Le Monde Musicale, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Locke, Matthew, 1621 or 2-1677 title: The Original Music in Macbeth Publisher: G. Walker, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Autographed Sheet Music
  - Pennington, John title: Alpine Scenes Publisher: Schmidt, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    autographed by composer
  - Shelly, Harry Rowe. title: American Dances Publisher: G. Schirmer, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    2 copies; autographed by composer
  - various title: Finlandia Publisher: westerlund, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    autographed by unknown
  - Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. title: Der Corregidor Publisher: Heckel, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    autographed by Rudolf Traxler
- Bound Scores
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 title: Brankenburgiches Konzert No. q Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 title: Quatre Etudes Publisher: Fromont, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 title: Das Wohltemperierte Kavier Publisher: J.G. Cottasche Bushhandlung Nachfolger, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 title: Chaconne Publisher: A. Buttner, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 title: Bach-Bufoni, Band IV, V, VI, VII Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 13 - 16)
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 title: Magdalena Publisher: Max Eschig, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 title: Das Wohltemperierte Kavier Publisher: C.F. Peters, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 title: Geistliche Lieder Von Gellert Publisher: Schuberth, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 title: Sonaten fur piano und violoncel Publisher: C.F. Peters, undated (Box 2, Folder 20 - 21)
    2 v.
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 title: Sonaten NR 16-32 Publisher: Ausgabe der Musicfreunde, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 title: Ludwig Van Beethoven's Werke: fur pianoforte und violine Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 title: Ouvres Completes pour le Piano Publisher:, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 title: Quartette Fur 2 Violinen, Bratsche und Violoncell, opus 41 Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 title: Oeuvres Completes pour le piano, Vol. 1-2, 3-4, 5-6 Publisher: P.J. Jurgenson, undated (Box 3, Folder 26 - 28)
    3 v.
  - Chopin, Frederic, 1810-1849 title: Thematisches Verzeichniss der im Druck erschienenen Compositionen Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Chopin, Frederic, 1810-1849 title: Funf Specialstudien fur Pianoforte Publisher: U.E. 1285; Universal-Edition A. G., 1899 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Chopin, Frederic, 1810-1849 title: Samtliche Klavierwerke, Band V Publisher: Steingraber, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Chopin, Frederic, 1810-1849 title: Oeuvres completes: revenues, doigtees et soigneusement corrigees d'apres les editions de Paris, Londres, Bruxelles et Leipsic Publisher: Ed.Bote & G. Bock, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    v.3
  - Chopin, Frederic, 1810-1849 title: Chopin Album: A collection of thirty-two favorite compositions Publisher: B. F. Wood Music Company, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Chopin, Frederic, 1810-1849 title: Fr. Chopin's Sammtliche Pianoforte-Werke Publisher: C.F.Peters, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 34 - 37)
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828 title: Sonates pour piano de Schubert Publisher: Braunschweig, 1840 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828 title: Marches and Symphonies Publisher: C.F.Peters, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Published separately, bound together
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828 title: Sonatas and Dances Publisher: C.F.Peters, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Mendelssohn, Felix, 1809-1847 title: Thematisches Verzeichniss im Druck erschienener Compositionen von Felix Mendelssohn Bartholdy Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, 1846 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Mendelssohn, Felix, 1809-1847 title: Felix Mendellsohn-Bartholdy's Sammtliche Compositionen fur Pianoforte Solo Publisher: C.F. Peters, undated (Box 5, Folder 42 - 43)
  - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 title: Chamber music. Selections: Kammermusik Band I- IV Publisher: Ernst Eulenburg, undated (Box 12, Folder 146-149)
  - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 title: Chamber music. Selections: Symphonien, Band II Publisher: Ernst Eulenburg, undated (Box 12, Folder 150)
  - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 title: Ubungen fur das pianoforte Publisher: N. Simrock, 1883 (Box 6, Folder 66.2)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791 title: Symphonie C: (Jupiter) kochel No. 551 Publisher: Wiener Philharmonischer Verlag, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 151)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791 title: Ausgewahlte Sonaten und Andere Stucke Publisher: Cotta, 1890-1891 (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791 title: Oeuvres Completes pour Piano de Mozart Publisher:, undated (Box 17, Folder 153-154)
  - Fellowes, Edmund Horace, 1870-1951, ed. title: Madrigals, voices Publisher: Stainer & Bell, 1914-1916 (Box 13, Folder 155-164)
  - Fellowes, Edmund Horace, 1870-1951, ed. title: Madrigals, voices Publisher: Stainer & Bell, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 165-167)
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893 title: Die Jungfrau von Orleans Publisher:, undated (Box 16, Folder 168)
- Miscellaneous
  - Alkan, Charles-Valentin, 1813-1888 title: 3 Airs a Cinq Temps et 1 a Sept Temps pour piano Publisher: C. Joubert, 1905 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Bach, Wilhelm Friedemann, 1710-1784 title: Suite G moll; Sonaten, und kleinere Werke fur Pianoforte Publisher:, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 title: Concert fur das Pianoforte Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    Published separately, bound together: A.B.Grondahl;O.Bull;C.Cappelen;C.Elling;E.Grieg;J.Haarklou;O..Winter-Hjelm;J.Holter;H.Kjerulf;G.Lange;B.Lasson;P.Lasson;L.M.Lindeman;E.Neupert;R.Nordraak;O.Olsen;J.Selmer;C.Sinding;J.Svendsen;C.Teilman;T.D.A.Tellefsen;P.Winge.
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 - engraved portrait, undated (Box 4, Item *)
  - Berners, Gerald Hugh Tyrwhitt-Wilson, Baron, 1883-1950 title: Valses Bourgeoises, Duet for the piano forte Publisher: J. & W. Chester, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Blanchet, E. R., 1877-1943 title: Divertimento, pour piano, op.47 Publisher: Max Eschig, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Chabrier, Emmanuel, 1841-1894 title: Impromptu pour piano Publisher: Enoch & Editeurs, undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Chabrier, Emmanuel, 1841-1894 title: Joyeuse Marche Publisher: Enoch, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Chabrier, Emmanuel, 1841-1894 title: Joyeuse Marche Publisher: Enoch, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Chabrier, Emmanuel, 1841-1894 title: Suite de Valses, (Oeuvre Posthume) Publisher: Costallat, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Chabrier, Emmanuel, 1841-1894 title: Suite de Valses, (Oeuvre Posthume) Publisher: Costallat, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Durante, Francesco, 1684-1755 title: Composizioni per cembalo Publisher: Societa Anonima Notari, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Dvorak, Antonin, 1841-1904 title: Concert fur Pianoforte und Orchester, Op.33 Publisher:, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Fuller-Maitland, J. A., 1856-1936 title: The Fitzwilliam Virginal Book Publisher: Broude Brothers, 1949 (Box Shelf, Folder 79 - 80)
  - Gershwin, George, 1898-1937 title: Rhapsody in blue, Two piano edition Publisher: Harms, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 86 - 87)
  - Gound, Charles, 1818-1893 title: Oeuvres Inedites. Autographes de Faust, Romeo et Juliette… Publisher: Paris, 1896 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    Composers: N.H.Allen, H.N.Bartlett; Francis Boott; G.F.Bristow; G.A.Burdett; G.W. Chadwick; H.A.Clarke; H.A.Clarke; J.H. Cornell, L.Damrosch;J.R.Fairlamb;A.E.Fisher;A.Foote;W.W.Gilchrist;F.J.Hatton;W.J.Henderson; R.hoffman; F.G.Ilsley; G.Ingraham; E.Marzo; H. Millard; J.L.Molloy; J.Mosenthal;J.W.Palmer; W.S.Pratt; S.B.Schlesinger;W.G.Smith; A.A.Stanley; G.J. Stoeckel; E.B.Story; G.F.Suck; S.P.Warren.
  - Guilbert, Yvette, 1865-1944 title: Legendes dorees, avec leurs airs anciens Publisher: B. Schott's Sohne, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Hamilton, Adam title: The Scottish Orpheus Publisher: Boosey & Co., undated (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Herold, Ferdinand, 1791-1833 title: 2me Symphonie, (Oeuvre Posthume) Publisher: Felix Mackar, 1887 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Herscher, J., editor title: Transcriptions pour le piano d'oeuvres d'orgue Publisher: E. Demets, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Title: Jubilaeum-Album; Album pianofortemusik af norske komponister Publisher: Christiania: Carl Warmuths Forlag, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Jones, Robert, active 1597-1615: "Excellent Good Songs of Mr. Jones"; Transcribed from the original editions of 1601 and 1608, 1920s (Box 6, Folder 66.1)
    Heseltine, Philip Arnold (1894-1930) -- transcriber; Warlock, Peter, 1894-1930-- transcriber
  - Kjerulf, Halfdan, 1815-1868 title: Halfdan Kjerulf's Album of Songs Publisher: O. Ditson & Co., 1885 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Lebert, Sigmund, 1821-1884 title: Grosse Theoretisch-Praktische Klavierschule Publisher: J. G. Cotta'schen Buchhandlung, 1872 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Locatelli, Pietro Antonio, 1695-1764 title: Composizioni, Quaretto N.3 Publisher: Societa Anonima Notari, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Macdowell, Edward, 1860-1908 title: Compositions for the pianoforte, New Editions Revised by the Composer (Opus 13, 16-19, 24, 36-37; Six sketches; After Bach) Publisher: Arthur P. Schmidt, undated (Box Shelf, Folder 90)
  - Macdowell, Edward, 1860-1908 title: Four Sonatas; Op. 45, 50, 57,59 Publisher: Breitkopf & Hart, undated (Box Shelf, Folder 91a)
    Theater program
  - Macdowell, Edward, 1860-1908 title: Klavier Bibliothek: Erste modern suite, Op.10; Zweite moderne Suite, Op.14; Vier kleine Poesien, Op.32; Virtuosen-Etuden, Op.46) Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, undated (Box Shelf, Folder 89)
  - Macdowell, Edward, 1860-1908 title: Six Poems after Heine; Six Idyls after Goethe; Woodland Sketches; Sea Pieces; Fireside Tales; New England Idyls; 12 Etudes; Publisher: Arthur P. Schmidt, 1901 (Box Shelf, Folder 88)
  - Martini, Giovanni Battista, 1706-1784 title: Sonate per pianoforte Publisher: Societa Anonima Notari, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    2 copies
  - Muffat, Gottlieb, 1690-1770 title: Zwolf Toccaten und 72 Versetl, fur Orgel und Klavier Publisher: Universal Edition, undated (Box 6, Folder 91b)
  - Nicode, Jean Louis, 1853-1919 title: Ein Liebesleben, op.22 Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Paradies, Pietro Domenico, 1707-1791 title: Sonate per pianoforte Publisher: Societa Anonima Notari, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Pratt, Waldo S. title: St. Nicholas Songs Publisher: The Century Co., 1885 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Rameau, Jean-Philippe, 1683-1764 title: 5 Klavierkonzerte Publisher: Steingraber-Verlag, undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Reinecke, Carl, 1824-1910 title: Clavier-Concerte alter und neuer Zeit. Bach, Beethoven, Chopin… Publisher: Leipzig, Breitkopf & Harter, 1875 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Reinecke, Carl, 1824-1910 title: Clavier-Concerte alter und neuer Zeit Publisher: Leipzig, Breitkopf & Harter, undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Reinecke, Carl, 1824-1910 title: Sonatinen fur das pianoforte Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, undated (Box 6, Folder 83)
    (Ivme acte, scene 1re, pour grand orchestre, op.12
  - Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908 title: Scheherazade; d'apres Mille et une nuits Publisher: M. P. Belaieff, 1889 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    Published separately, bound together: Wolf, Hugo; Felix Weingartner; W. F. G. Nicolai; Frank La Forge; Arthur Foote; Magdalen S. Worden; H. W. Loomis; Hermann Lohr; Ethelbert Nevin; H. T. Burleigh; Arthur Whiting; B. O. Klein; Victor Herbert; Homer N. Bartlett; Wilson G. Smith; Carl A. Preyer
  - Rutini, Giovanni Marco, 1723-1797 title: Sonate per pianoforte Publisher: Societa Anonima Notari, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 title: 50 Harpsichord Lessons Publisher: Augener & Company, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Schirmer's Household Series of Music Books, No.40 title: Modern song favorites, vol.I, a collection of twenty-five favorite songs: high voice Publisher:, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Schirmer's Library of Musical Classics, Vol.291 title: Anthology of Italian Song of the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries, vol.II Publisher: G. Schirmer, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Smetana, Bedrich, 1824-1884 title: Caprice Publisher: Nakladem Umelecke Besedy, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Tcherepnine, Nicolas, 1873-1945 title: Scene dans la caverne des sorcieres Publisher: Belaieff, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 91c)
  - Turrini, Ferdinando, 1749-1812 title: Sonata per cembalo Publisher: Societa Anonima Notari, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Wells, Walter J. title: Souvenir of Sir Arthur Sullivan Publisher: George Newnes, Limited, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Zichy, Geza, 1849-1924 title: Serenade pour la main gauche seule Publisher: Harmonia, 1882 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Zichy, Geza, 1849-1924 title: Sonate fur Piano fur die linke Hand allein Publisher: D. Rahter, undated (Box 6, Folder 81 - 82)
  - The Beethoven House at Bonn: and its collections, 1962 (Box Shelf, Item 92)
  - Johannes Brahms Briefwschsel, v 1, 2, and 5, 1912-1921 (Box Shelf, Item 93)
  - A Christmas Family-Party by Charles Dickens/ Redcoat Press: Westport, CT., 1966 (Box Shelf, Item 94)
  - Famous Composers, by John Knowles Paine, 1 volume, 1891 (Box Shelf, Item 95)
  - Fu¨hrer durch den konzertsaal, ?c von Hermann Kretzschmar (I, IIi, IIii), 1913 (Box Shelf, Item 98)
  - "Mrs. Emanuel Untermeyer" imprint on cover title: Songs and piano solos Publisher:, undated (Box Shelf, Folder 96)
  - Proceedings of the Musical Association, 1904-1905 (Box Shelf, Item 97)
- Operas/Oratories/Vocal Music
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868 title: Elisabetta, Regina d'Inghilterra Publisher: Breitkopf & Hart, 1819 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868 title: Il Turco in Italia Publisher: Breitkopf & Hart, 1823 (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868 title: Armida Publisher: Breitkopf & Hart, undated (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 title: Das Rheingold Publisher: B. Schott's Sohne, undated (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848 title: Linda di Chamounix opera in three acts Publisher: New York Theatre Ticket Office, undated (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826 title: Der Freischutz; A Grand Opera in Three Acts Publisher: unknown, undated (Box 10, Folder 98)
    Autographed by Deems Taylor
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 title: Siegfried, Klavierauszug zu zwei Handen Publisher: B. Schott's Sohne, undated (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - No author title: No title page, Edition Peters Publisher: W. Sulzbach, undated (Box 8, Folder 100 - 101)
  - No author title: Operas Publisher: Various publishers, undated (Box 11, Folder 102)
  - No author title: Die Zigeunerin. Romantische Oper in drei Acteu; and, Lakme, Opera en 3 Actes Publisher: P. Mechetti, undated (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868 title: Der Barbier von Sevilla Publisher: C. F. Peters, undated (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Bellini, Vincenzo, 1801-1835 title: Die Nachtwandlerin Publisher: C. F. Peters, undated (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirevich, 1833-1887 title: Le Prince Igor, Opera en quatre actes avec prologue Publisher: M. P. Belaieff, 1888 (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - Dvorak, Antonin, 1841-1904 title: Stabat Mater, Op.58 Publisher: G. Schirmer, Inc., undated (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Verdi, Giusepppe, 1813-1901 title: La Traviata, Opera in three acts Publisher: G. Schirmer, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 title: Christus, Oratorium Publisher: J. Schuberth, 1872 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893 title: Margarethe (Faust), Oper in funf acten Publisher: Bote & Bock, undated (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Handel, Georg Friedrich, 1685-1759 title: Debora, Oratorium Publisher: Breitkopf u. Hartel, 1909 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - Smetana, Bedrich, 1824-1884 title: Dve Vdovy, Definitivn Smetanova uprava s recitativy z roku 1877 Publisher: Hudebni Matice Umelecke Besedy, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - Smetana, Bedrich, 1824-1884 title: Tajemstvi, komicka zpevohra o trech dejstvich Publisher: Hudebni Matice Umelecke Besedy, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Smetana, Bedrich, 1824-1884 title: Dve Vdovy, Definitivn Smetanova uprava s recitativy z roku 1877 Publisher: Hudebni Matice Umelecke Besedy, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Paisiello, Giovanni, 1740-1816 title: Le barbier de Seville. Opera en quatre acts Publisher: Heugel, undated (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - Handel, Georg Friedrich, 1685-1759 title: The Messiah Publisher: G. Schirmer, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 116)
  - Cimarosa, Domenico, 1749-1801 title: Heinliche Ehe Publisher: C. F. Peters, undated (Box 9, Folder 117)
    Published separately, bound together (Beethoven, Herold, Planquette)
  - Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864 title: Der Prophet Publisher: C. F. Peters, 1895 (Box 10, Folder 118)
  - Handel, Georg Friedrich, 1685-1759 title: Salomo, Oratorium Publisher: C. F. Peters, undated (Box 10, Folder 119)
  - Nicolai, Otto, 1810-1849 title: Overture to the opera The Merry Wives of Windsor Publisher: Bote & Bock, undated (Box 10, Folder 120)
    Text.No.1, Paulus
  - Handel, Georg Friedrich, 1685-1759 title: Handel's Oratorien, im Clavierauszug Publisher: Simrock, undated (Box 12, Folder 121)
  - Handel, Georg Friedrich, 1685-1759 title: Ezio, Oper in drei Akten nach Metastasio Publisher: A. J. Benjamin, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 122)
  - Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826 title: Abu Hassan Publisher: Universal Edition, undated (Box 12, Folder 123)
  - Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899 title: Indigo und die vierzig Rauber Publisher: Cranz, undated (Box 12, Folder 124)
  - No author title: No title Publisher: C. F. Peters, undated (Box 15, Folder 125)
  - Delibes, Leo, 1836-1891 title: Lakme. Opera en 3 acts Publisher: Heugel & Fils, 1883 (Box 15, Folder 126)
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893 title: Pique-Dame, Op.68 Publisher: D. Rahter, 1895 (Box 14, Folder 127)
    Werk 345
  - Stern, Julius, 1820-1883 title: Oratorien von Felix Mendelssohn-Bartholdy Publisher: Verlag und Eigenthum von N. Simrock, undated (Box 15, Folder 128)
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 title: Szenen aus Goethe's Faust Publisher: C. F. Peters, undated (Box 14, Folder 129)
  - Handel, Georg Friedrich, 1685-1759 title: Tamerlan Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 130)
  - Handel, Georg Friedrich, 1685-1759 title: Floridante Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, 1895 (Box 14, Folder 131)
  - Handel, Georg Friedrich, 1685-1759 title: Theodora Publisher: Rieter-Biedermann, 1870 (Box 14, Folder 132)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791 title: Idomeneo Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, undated (Box 14, Folder 133)
    Vol. 1: La Traviata, Tannhauser, Mignon, Faust, Cavalleria Rusticana, The Rhinegold, The Valkyrie, Siegfried, Gotterdammerung, Stradella. Vol.2: Martha, Semiramide, Manon, Norma, Marriage of Figaro, Aida, Der Freischutz, La Dame Blanche, Sapho, Lucia di Lammermoor. Vol.3: Orpheus and Eurydice, The Huguenots, Il Trovatore, Carmen, The Jewess, The Flying Dutchman, Fidelio, Lohengrin, Hansel and Gretel, Don Giovanni. Vol. 4: Nero, I Puritani, The Master Singers, Lakme, Samson and Delilah, Tristan and Isolde, The Magic Flue, The Bohemian Gril, La Boheme, Queen of Sheba. Vol.5: The Prophet, Lucretia Borgia, William Tell, Robert the Devil, Fra Diabolo, The Barber of Seville, L'Africaine, La Favorita, La Sonnambula, Rigoletto.
  - Sullivan, Arthur, 1842-1900; Gilbert, W. S. title: Princess Ida, or, Castle Adamant Publisher: Chappell, undated (Box 15, Folder 134)
    Series: Payne's kleine Partitur-Ausgabe.
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791 title: Thamos, Konig in Agypten Publisher: Breitkopf & Hart, undated (Box 16, Folder 135)
    Series: Eulenburg's kleine Orchester-Partitur-Ausgabe
  - Humperdinck, Engelbert, 1854-1921 title: Hansel und Gretel Publisher: B.Schott's Sohne, undated (Box 16, Folder 136)
  - Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869 title: Benvenuto Cellini Publisher: H. Verlag, undated (Box 16, Folder 137)
    Volume 1 and 2, bound together
  - Dvorak, Antonin, 1841-1904 title: Jakobin Publisher: Hudebni Matice Umelecke Besedy, 1928 (Box 16, Folder 138)
    Vol. I: Sonates et Airs Varies. Vol. II: Concertos et compositions a 2 et 4 mains.
  - Gretry, Andre-Ernest-Modeste, 1741-1813 title: Richard Loewenherz Irichard Coeur-de-lion) Publisher: Verlag von Bartholf Senff, undated (Box 14, Folder 139)
    Vol. V Orlando Gibbons; Vols. VI-VII John Wilbye; Vol. VIII John Farmer; Vols. IX to XIII Thomas Weelkes